KELLY MARIA HILL

420 W. Slaughter Lane, Apt. #417 • Austin, TX 78748 • (504) 432-8327 • <u>Kelly.m.hill2115@gmail.com</u> https://codefitness21.github.io/Portfolio/ • https://github.com/Codefitness21?tab=repositories

SUMMARY

Tech-focused fitness professional transitioning into the IT world, with project experience across front-end web development. Key strengths include consulting with clients to develop personalized health solutions, creating and delivering educational presentations, and applying technology to real world challenges. Analytical thinker and creative problem-solver, able to quickly learn, apply, and troubleshoot new technologies in fast-paced environments.

SKILLS PROFILE

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Platforms/Systems: GitHub, Visual Studio Code, Terminal

Techniques: Responsive Design, Preprocessing, Arrays, Objects, DOM, Components, API

Workshops/ Classes: Austin Coding Academy – Learn to Code

Girls in Tech Coding Bootcamp: Intro to JS Developer Week Hackathon Conference Black Women Talk Tech – Austin Chapter

Technology + Art: How Data and Algorithms Enable New Artistic Creativity

Women Who Code: Hacking Hangout Codecademy – Web Development Khan Academy – HTML, CSS, JS Udemy – Modern React with Redux

EXPERIENCE

2017 – Present Life Time Fitness Austin, TX

Certified Personal Trainer/Nutritionist/Metabolic Technician

- Assess the nutritional and physical health of clients and collaborate to implement holistic fitness programs addressing specific health needs, in addition to providing tools to support continual advancement in both the fitness center and at home
- Utilize a range of technological tools, application software, and technical solutions to assess caloric intake, resting metabolic rate, and active metabolic rate to develop customized plans and monitor progress
- Collaborate with the metabolic specialist and tech team to share knowledge, analytical data, and technical solutions to promote sustainable client progress and success

2016 – 2017 24 Hour Fitness Austin, TX

Certified Personal Trainer/Nutritionist

- Designed individualized exercise programs tailored to the goals and needs of clients
- Advised clients on proper nutritional planning and demonstrated use of fitness apps to help track progress

Dietetic Intern 2014 – 2015

- Led nutrition groups and conducted screenings and assessments for patients
- Created and delivered presentations on recommendations and education to patients, athletes, and fellow students

Graduate Assistant 2012 – 2013

 Instructed a Nutrition Food Systems laboratory, and assisted the professor with research and grant writing, in addition to grading exams and research papers

PROJECTS

Weather App 2020

Built an app displaying global temperatures using React and API

American Football Scorecard 2020

Used React to develop an app displaying a scoreboard for an American football game

Fun Bus 2020

 Created a modern web design for travel blogs, using a LESS compiler to add a stylized navigation bar, header, and buttons

Responsive Design 2020

 Created a web page to demonstrate a flexible and compatible design for desktops, tablets, and mobile devices

Great Idea! 2020

 Designed a web page project, creating a user interface from scratch utilizing the provided design file and inline-block to reorganize the code from a scrambled layout, and refactored using flexbox

Let's Get Motivated 2019

 Utilized JavaScript to create an application generating random motivational quotes to support fitness aspirations

EDUCATION

Texas State University San Marcos, TX

Master of Science, Human Nutrition (2015)

University of New Orleans New Orleans, LA

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology (2004)